(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners, welcome
back to English, POD, my name is Marco.
- And my name is Catherine,
and today Marco and
I get to share with you
the thrilling conclusion
to the, well, very
popular, I must say, series.
I'm sorry, I love you.
- That's right, today is the finale,
the final episode, episode
10, this is where it all ends.
So what do you think is gonna happen?
- If I guess, you're just gonna get angry
at me 'cause I actually know how it ends.
- Well, let's just say, I hope
that it ends well for protagonists.
- There was a lot of controversy around it
because, you know, I
wanted to know if people
wanted a happy ending,
a sad ending, unexpected.
I guess everyone wants
a happy ending, right?
- Absolutely, so we're gonna,
well, keep our fingers crossed
for Stephen and Veronica and
check out this dialogue one time.
(upbeat music)
- Stephen, good to see you brother.
How are you?
How was your trip?
- It was fine.
I've been better, but
it's great to be home.
I've missed you all.
How's mom?
- She's great.
All she ever does is talk about you or
little boy that eventually United States.
- You're her pride and
joy, you know that, right?
- Can't wait to see you.
- You, what's new with you?
- Well, Nisha and I are expecting,
you'll have another nephew or niece soon.
- That's great.
Wow, congrats.
- You two are great together, you know.
You have such a beautiful family.
I hope that one day I can have that.
- Of course, man, come on.
I mean, everything was said
here for you to marry Shalini.
You know, she's still finding out for you.
I don't think she'll ever get over you.
- You're talking about, I hardly knew her.
How could she be in love with me?
I can go through with it even
though she is a great woman.
- No, I left my heart in the United States.
I just hope Veronica is happy.
Get over it, you're home now.
Everyone here, thanks so highly of you.
They'll be girls throwing
themselves at you.
You can marry anyone you want.
I don't wanna marry anyone.
- I wanna marry her, don't you understand?
- You are incredible.
- Steven, my baby, how are you?
I miss you so much.
- You mom, great to see you.
- You look so thin.
They didn't do some Americans with you.
Come, come, let's have some time.
By the way, there is a
girl here waiting for you.
Hi Steven.
- Veronica, how did you get here?
How do you know where I live?
I waited for you at the
airport, but you never showed.
I also have some little
secrets that I haven't
told you about, but
we can discuss that later.
I realized that I was just scared,
scared of how much I love you
and of the commitment
that marriage requires.
I'm here now.
Now, there's something I wanna ask you.
Steven, will you marry me?
(upbeat music)
I now declare you husband and what?
You make this to grow.
- All right, so they got married.
- Oh, you got married.
- We got married, I got married.
- Wow, I should have called my mom.
- And not only did you get married,
but you got married Bollywood style
with like music and everything nice.
- No weddings are like four days long.
- I hope you enjoyed
the finale of this story.
- Absolutely, I was glad to
see that it was a happy ending.
I have to say, if it had
been a sad ending,
I would have been a
little bit disappointed
because, well, Veronica
and I, you get along.
- We get along.
- All right, so apart from this happy
ending and this happy finale that we had,
we did look at a lot of
great words and phrases.
So why don't we start now
with language takeaway?
- Language takeaway.
So the first couple of phrases
we want to talk about here
have to do with maybe
catching up and talking about
family or gossip because
we're talking to a family member.
- A family member.
- Stevens in the in family, we
haven't seen for a long, long time.
And the first thing he's talking to his
brother about his brother and his wife.
So Goulam and Nisha
are expectingly find out.
- Right, they're expecting.
So if Goulam and Nisha are
expecting, what does that mean exactly?
- They're expecting a letter.
- Expecting a baby maybe?
- Ah, hi, yeah, so there we go.
I'm expecting, it's very
common English way of
saying, I'm going to
have a baby, I'm pregnant.
- All right, so don't get this confused.
If somebody says, oh, well, I'm expecting,
you don't have to say expecting what?
- Exactly, when it's only
expecting when it's not a
thing afterwards, I'm
expecting means I'm pregnant
or she's expecting,
she's gonna have a baby.
So they are expecting a
baby or they're expecting.
Well, and they were talking about, well,
Stephen, he was supposed
to get married in India
and his brother said a
very interesting word.
He said, well, these girls are
still, this girl is still pining over you.
- So the shalini, some girl
that Stephen used to know
when he was living in
India, she's pining after you.
Well, pine has many different
meanings than you guys.
But in this sense, we're talking about
having a crush on or being in love with.
- And also it's a way of
saying that you desire,
you yearn for this
person very, very much.
- But that you don't have them.
- Right, you want them.
- You want them.
So you're pining over this person.
Now, can you pine over an object?
- No, no, usually it's maybe related
to love or to in a person, right?
- Yeah, so she stands by the door every
day waiting the letter that doesn't come.
She's pining away for her
dear love, Thomas or whatever.
And you know what I've read recently
is that people can get addicted to pining.
- Really?
- Yeah, after a breakup, maybe you can pine
after a person, not because you miss them
or you want to put, you
kind of grow a custom to it
and you become addicted to
this pain that's kind of pleasurable.
- There is a way to describe
this, it's called Petrarch in Love.
Well, it's this kind of
traditional idea in poetry
where you have a love that's never
consummated, that's never filled.
You never get to be with the
person that you love that you desire.
And so it's a way,
yeah, it's a way of
distinguishing the two
different kinds of love.
One where you're with
the person and the other
where you always want them,
but you can never have them.
- Well, hopefully none of our listeners
are pining over anyone or
get to experience that, huh?
- Exactly, but if you do pine
away or you pine after someone,
you have to hope that one
day you'll get over that person.
- Yeah, you have to get over it and that's
what his brother says, "Hey, get over it.
" - I don't think she'll
ever get over you.
- So what does it mean when
you're supposed to get over someone?
- Okay, this is a good
question because, you know,
we're talking here not about actually
getting up on top of a fence or a wall.
We're talking about emotions.
So getting over someone,
so I have to get over him
means that I have to stop feeling
so sad about what happened, right?
Because usually you say this
when someone's sad or angry.
- And also it kind of means
that you have to forget
or let that person go,
you know, like, get over it.
- We're gonna move on
here too to the last word
in today's language
takeaway, which is incorrigible.
- Okay, an incorrigible person.
- All right, incorrigible,
what could this mean?
Well, let's look at the
sentence where we find it.
You are incorrigible, hmm,
Gullam says this to Stephen.
- Right, so it's an
adjective and basically it
means that you have no
correction of some sort.
- Well, there's an argument
between Stephen and Gullam.
So they're brothers and Stephen says,
I don't wanna get married,
I don't wanna marry her.
Ah, he's complaining and his brother says,
you are incorrigible, you just won't stop.
- Right, so someone's
feelings, their emotions,
their ideas about
something, they just can't be
changed or altered their
fixed, you know, this guy.
He's like, I'm not gonna get married
and his brother says,
oh, you're incorrigible.
I just can't change your mind.
- It's kind of like being stubborn.
- Yeah, yeah, exactly.
And we hear this phrase a lot together.
So you're incorrigible, right?
So this is often just kind
of a, it's a, it's not an insult,
but it's way for us to kind of be
sarcastic or to make fun of someone.
You're an incorrigible
Marco, usually you say,
when you're lying, you
know, you'd be nice, all right.
- Okay, cool, so five great words
in language takeaway today.
And well, before we move
on and listen to the dialogue,
again, why don't we take
a look at fluency builder?
- Fluency builder, all right.
This first phrase is something
that parents often use
and grandparents as well,
because obviously parents
and grandparents are very proud of
their children and their grandchildren.
So they describe something
as being their pride and joy.
- My pride and joy.
So it's usually a person
that's your pride and joy.
- It could be a thing too.
- It could be a thing.
- His Porsche Boxster is his pride and joy.
He goes out every morning and he washes
it, he changes the oil, he checks the gas,
he checks the tires,
so it's his pride and joy.
- All right.
- It's his most valued possession.
- So it always goes together, right?
My pride and joy.
- Pride and joy.
Yeah, just think of it as
a phrase, pride and joy.
- All right.
- So I'm my mother's pride and joy.
- I think you are.
- Mm.
(laughing)
- All right, so you're not my mom.
- All right, so somebody's pride and joy.
So now another phrase that we took a look
at and it's a way of making conversation,
especially with a person
that you haven't seen
in a while, he said, hey,
what's new with you?
- What's new with you?
- Uh-huh, what's new with you?
- All right, so this might
sound a little strange
because normally we
say, how have you been?
It's been a long time.
- How are you?
- But this is like, you know,
it's a fluency builder phrase.
So it's very colloquial,
it's very spoken language.
So this you hear often between
friends or family members.
Hey, Marco, what's new with you?
- So how do you, I would
answer this by saying,
I will not much or I just
bought a new house.
So basically you're asking
for news from person.
- I haven't seen you in a long time.
You look happy and healthy.
So what's new with you?
Oh, I got married, I got a new car.
These things that you can
say, these are changes in my life.
- All right, and usually after somebody
asks you, what's new with you?
You say something and
then you usually would
follow up and ask that
person as well, right?
What's new with you?
- Exactly, so I got a new
house, got a new job.
What's new with you?
- Yeah, or what about you?
- What about you?
- It's a nice, very relaxed, informal, way
of asking someone for news in their life.
- Perfect, all right, what's new with you?
What else?
Now, he was supposed to get married, right?
- Right, so this is news, he
was supposed to get married.
He didn't get married, what's going on?
His brother, his mother, they
all wanna know what's going on.
And we find out that wedding, that
girl, he just couldn't go through with it.
- So I couldn't go through with it.
- Okay, this past tense, so
he's saying, before I came
to India with this girl, I
couldn't go through with it.
- So present would be, I
can't go through with it.
And going through with
what, here, we've got it, so
this kind of magical, strange
word, what could this be?
- So basically, what he's saying
is that he couldn't complete
or maybe finish something
that he started, right?
- So in this case, we're talking about
a relationship or
marriage, so maybe we love
each other, but I couldn't
go through with it,
I couldn't go to the finish line.
- Right, I couldn't get married.
You see that a lot, when maybe in movies,
two people are supposed to get married.
They're at the altar, and all of a sudden,
the bride says, I can't,
or she goes away crying.
- I can't go through with it.
- Exactly, right?
So because she loves somebody else,
so can't go through with it.
- Great, so really good phrase.
I can't go through with it,
he couldn't go through with it.
- And we find out that,
well, not such a bad thing,
Steven, he's very
popular in India, the girls.
Love him, we've got a great phrase for
describing having lots of girls who love you.
- Right, he says there'll be
girls throwing themselves at you.
- Literally, like, oh,
that might have hurt.
- I can imagine that, like, just
somebody throwing themselves at you.
No, it's not literally,
it's basically saying,
girls are very interested
in you, girls are so
interested in you that
they'll be chasing you almost.
- All right, so many, many girls,
they will follow you, they want to be
in a relationship with you, they like you.
- So he's saying, listen,
there are other girls.
Don't worry, girls hear, they love you.
- And it doesn't only
work with girls, right?
I can say, they'll be boys
throwing themselves at you.
- Right, so this is something
we say about both genders,
boys and girls, you can say, oh, God, all
the boys were throwing themselves at her.
I'm so jealous.
- Right, but it's only
basically in a loving way, right?
It can't be anything else, like
somebody's chasing you for other reasons.
- Now, this is saying
that they have crushes,
they have feelings,
they want to be romantic.
It's not like a, it's not a bad thing,
but sometimes it's too much attention,
so it can be kind of negative.
- Yeah, all right, well,
interesting phrases
on Fluency Builder today,
I think it's time for us
to listen to this
dialogue for one last time.
- Get up and dance.
- Yeah, get up and dance,
and we'll be back in a little bit.
(upbeat music)
- Steven, good to see you, brother.
How are you?
How was your trip?
- It was fine, I've been better, but it's
great to be home, I've missed you all.
How's mom?
- She's great, all she
ever does is talk about you
or a little boy that
eventually United States.
- You're her pride and
joy, you know that, right?
- Can't wait to see you.
- You, what's new with you?
- Well, Nisha and I are expecting,
you'll have another nephew or niece soon.
- That's great, wow, congrats!
- You two are great together, you know.
You have such a beautiful family.
I hope that one day I can have that.
- Of course, man, come on.
I mean, everything was said here for you
to marry Shallini, you know,
she's still planning after you.
I don't think she'll ever get over you.
- You're talking about, I hardly knew her.
How could she be in love with me?
I can go through with it, even
though she's a great woman.
No, I left my hard-made United States.
I just hope Veronica is happy.
- Get over it, you're home now.
Everyone here thinks so highly of you.
They'll be girls throwing
themselves at you.
You can marry anyone you want.
- I don't wanna marry anyone.
- I wanna marry her, don't you understand?
- You are incorrigible.
- Steven, my baby, how are you?
I miss you so much.
- You mom, great to see you.
- You look so thin.
They didn't those Americans feed you.
Come, come, let's have some time.
By the way, there is a
girl here waiting for you.
Hi, Steven.
- Veronica, how did you get here?
How do you know where I live?
I waited for you at the
airport, but you never showed.
- I also have some little
secrets that I haven't
told you about, but
we can discuss that later.
I realized that I was just scared.
Scared of how much I love you and of
the commitment that marriage requires.
I'm here now.
Now, there's something I wanna ask you.
Steven, will you marry me?
- I now declare you husband
and wife, you may kiss the girl.
- All right, so it's over.
- Sad, sad but sweet.
- Sad but sweet, huh, 10?
Well, we went from them
meeting casually by a bike accident.
- Yeah, we had nice music.
Then it turned out that she was angry.
They kind of broke up,
they got back together.
- He was being strained with all
of these secret trips to save people.
- Mm-hmm, it was interesting.
We went a lot of different ways.
- She was pregnant, she
wasn't really pregnant.
- The doctor was stalking him.
- Doctor, he's in the secret service.
- It was an interesting ride.
- Very interesting.
- Well, now we need
to think of a new drama,
a new soap opera or
novel, so we need your input.
Maybe we should open
it up, what did you like?
What didn't you like?
And what kind of genre
are you interested in?
Because, you know, there's tons of
different kinds of stories we could tell.
- Right, maybe we can do something scary,
like a thriller or horror.
- I'm a big fan of sci-fi.
- Or sci-fi, maybe we
can do something sci-fi.
Maybe we can do a comedy, something
maybe like friends, I don't know.
- That'd be kind of cute.
- Yeah, it could be.
All right, so listeners, why
don't you give us your input?
We need your feedback, tell us what series
we would like next, what
type of series, maybe,
like we said, drama, sci-fi,
action, what would you like?
- And please get in touch
with us, leave comments
and questions at our
website, EnglishPod.com.
We like to check those and answer you.
So, yeah, get in touch with
us and have a great day.
- All right, we'll see you guys there.
Bye.
(upbeat music)